<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History of computer technology | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/history-of-computer-technology/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/history-of-computer-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>History of computer technology</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>History of computer technology</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/history-of-computer-technology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>C. Babbage&#39;s Analytical engine</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;biography&#34;&gt;Biography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles Babbage was born in the family of banker Benjamin Babbage, on December 26, 1791. Due to poor health, Charles did not attend school. By the age of eleven, the parents still decide to send Charles to a private school. After graduating from this school, he is sent to the academy in Enfield, where he gets acquainted with the textbook that determined the passion of his entire later life.. In 1811, Charles became a student at Trinity College. There he meets other gifted students. Together they organized an &amp;ldquo;Analytical Society&amp;rdquo; within the walls of the university. After Cambridge, Charles lectured, worked together with Herschel on scientific work related to electricity. He wrote books and tried to engage in politics. In addition, Babbage was interested in engineering, in particular the work of trains. He invented the triangular device &amp;ldquo;sweeper&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-project-of-the-analytical-machine&#34;&gt;The project of the Analytical machine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1834, Babbage thought about creating a universal machine that would allow solving the entire class of computational problems. He assumed that building a new machine would require less time and money than finalizing a difference machine, since it had to consist of simpler mechanical elements. He provided the following parts in the analytical engine: 1. Warehouse 2. Factory or mill 3. Control device 4. Information input/output devices. The amount of memory was supposed to be a thousand numbers of 50 decimal places. Babbage decided to use punch cards to enter data into memory and control the operation of the machine. It was also possible to organize conditional execution of operations and cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-an-analytical-machine&#34;&gt;Creating an Analytical Machine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that Babbage described in detail the design of the Analytical Engine and the principles of its operation, it was never built during his lifetime. There were many reasons for this, but the main ones were the complete lack of funding for the project to create an Analytical Machine and the low level of technology at that time. It was only after the death of Charles Babbage that his son continued the business his father had started. In 1906, Henry, together with the Monroe company, built a working model of the car. Charles Babbage&amp;rsquo;s greatest achievement was the development of the principles underlying modern computers, a century before the technical possibility of their implementation appeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attitude of contemporaries to this scientist changed over time from a genius to an eccentric and even to an inventor who lost his mind on the basis of computers. The president of the Royal Society, Lord Ross, wrote that &amp;ldquo;Babbage, only with his inventions in the field of mechanical engineering, fully reimbursed the funds that the government invested in the construction of his difference machine.&amp;rdquo; The idea that was born in the nineteenth century and became a reality in the twentieth century, made a revolution not only in science, but also in our daily life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
